Preliminary Inventory to the Lesbian and Gay Labor Network Records WAG.092
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Lesbian and Gay Labor Network Records
1986-1991
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Lesbian and Gay Labor Network (New York, N.Y.)
Frank, Miriam
Holcomb, Desma
WAG.092
1 Linear Feet (1 box)
LGLN was founded in New York City in 1987 to promote lesbian and gay rights in unions and labor solidarity in the gay community. Activities include the Coors Boycott Coalition, publishing Pride at Work, organizing lesbian and gay committees in unions, and resource referral, particularly regarding AIDS in the workplace and domestic partnership benefits. The collection consists mainly of research files collected by Miriam Frank and Desma Holcomb for their book, Pride at Work. Also included are the organizational files, petition files, LGLN Newsletter, DC 37 Committee, and the Lesbian and Gay Teachers Association newsletter.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
LGLN was founded in New York City in 1987 by Desma Holcomb, Peter Tenney, Vivienne Freund, Harry Franklin and Shelley Ettinger as well as other lesbian and gay trade union activists to promote lesbian and gay rights in unions and labor solidarity in the gay community. Activities include the Coors Boycott Coalition, publishing Pride at Work, organizing lesbian and gay committees in unions, and resource referral, particularly regarding AIDS in the workplace and domestic partnership benefits.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged in the order in which they were recieved.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists mainly of research files collected by Miriam Frank and Desma Holcomb for their book, Pride at Work. Also included are the organizational files, petition files, LGLN Newsletter, DC 37 Committee, and the Lesbian and Gay Teachers Association newsletter.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Miriam Frank and Desma Holcomb, 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 1991.008.
Newsletters.; Unmarried couples |x Legal status, laws, etc.; AIDS (Disease) |x Patients |x Employment.; Gays |x Employment |z New York (State) |z New York.; Gay rights -- United States.; Labor unions |x Social aspects |z New York (State) |z New York.; Gay liberation movement |z New York (State) |z New York.; Lesbians |x Employment |z New York (State) |z New York.; Lesbian and Gay Teachers Association (New York, N.Y.); Ettinger, Shelley; Tenney, Peter; Frank, Miriam; Holcomb, Desma; Lesbian and Gay Labor Network (New York, N.Y.); Frank, Miriam; Holcomb, Desma
- AIDS in the Workplace, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- NYCOSH, SEMCOSH and OSHA on AIDS, 1989-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Unions and AIDS (Non-Hospital), 1987-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Surveys: AIDS, Employment, Domestic Partnership, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Aids and the Workplace--Legal Cases, 1988-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- World Health Organization Statement on AIDS, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Women and AIDS, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Interviews, Notes on AIDS, 1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Arts Unions and AIDS, 1989-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Hospital Unions and AIDS, 1989-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Domestic Partnership: Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Domestic Partnership: Interviews, Notes, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Domestic Partnership: Petitions, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- LGLN Newsletters, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- DC 37 Lesbian and Gay Issues Committee, 1988-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Lesbian and Gay Teachers Association, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous Clippings, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Publications, Pamphlets, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)